CHRYSOSTOMOS (MAKIS) MILAS

Junior Web Developer and QA tester with experience in front end technologies and UX/UI design.

CORE SKILLS QA TESTING, VUE.JS, HMTL, CSS, COMMUNICATION, BUGS IDENTIFICATION, TESTING





Risskov, Denmark



+45 50 33 30 63



makoulism@hotmail.com



Makis Milas | Linkedin

COMPETENCES

- Great flair for IT
- High interest and curiosity on new technologies
- Keen eye to detail and result driven mindset
- Ability to work without supervision and on own initiative
- High adaptability in any professional environment
- Time and project management
- Natural team player

SKILLS

- Experience with and exposure on HTML5, CSS3, Vue.js, JavaScript, Bootstrap 4.5, npm, Firebase, Figma, Git, Bitbucket, Slack, Jira, VS-Code, PHP7, jQuery, Node.js, MongoDB, GoormIDE
- WRF (Weather Research & Forecasting) model, GrADS, Matlab and Fortran
- Microsoft OfficeTM tools (WordTM, ExcelTM and PowerPointTM)

COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS

- Leadership Skills
- Communication Skills
- Coaching Skills
- Web development courses on Udemy

I'm a self-starter on web development with a M.Sc. degree, broad educational background and diverse working experience. I'm highly adaptable, passionate about succeeding in the field and goal oriented. I have moved to Aarhus from the UK with my partner ready to look for my next professional challenge.

<u>Makis Milas (online-portfolio-a916d.web.app)</u> <u>GreekCamps (murmuring-meadow-93919.herokuapp.com)</u>

WORK EXPERIENCE

November 2020 to January 2021

Developer Intern

DigitalGuest, Aarhus, Denmark

- QA and bug fixes on the platform
- UI/UX updates (HTML, CSS, Ant-design, FlexBox, BEM)
- Building new features (Vue.js, Firebase, Git)
- Close collaboration with internal and external partners
- Following SCRUM and agile methodologies to effectively communicate with different stakeholders

October 2018 to April 2020

Assistant Production Manager

Caffé Nero Roastery, London, United Kingdom

- Control room operator
- Organizing and optimizing daily production plan, overseeing that short and long term production is carried out to the required standards
- Managing the team of *Assistants to the production*, throughout the day
- Ensuring all lines of production run according to the BRC (British Retail Consortium) regulations including final product and packaging
- Having a methodical, accurate "Mechanical" attitude to enable monitoring all production machinery

November 2016 to September 2018

Assistant Store Manager

Caffé Nero Store, London, United Kingdom

- Responsible for running the shop, serving customers and keeping high hygiene standards
- Assigned to run every shift when on duty and to deal with store-related matters

LANGUAGES

- Greek (native)
- English (fluent)
- Danish (A1)
- French (basic)

INTERESTS

- Travelling abroad
- Sports (swimming, football)
- Music (concerts of different styles)
- Computer Games
- Languages
- Movies

REFERENCES

Available on request

September 2014 to February 2015

Junior PHP Developer (Internship)

Meteovista, Zeist, The Netherlands

- Project organization, creation of the workflow and running all scripts
- Deal with strict deadlines in order to deliver the final product successfully on time
- Give the scientific perspective on the ongoing application
- Write the PHP code under the Object Oriented Paradigm in the most efficient and clear way for further development
- Internship project: Derivation of wind field and forecast rain field out of a series of radar images. Performed alongside with an operational meteorologist as supervisor using PHP (OOP)

EDUCATION

2012 - 2015

M.Sc. Climate Studies

Meteorology and Air Quality Department Wageningen University, The Netherlands

- Demonstration of an in-depth theoretical and practical knowledge of natural and computer sciences
- Demonstration of considerable ability on project management, task prioritization and good time management
- M.Sc. Thesis: Dynamic Coupling of Sudden Stratospheric Warmings with Tropospheric Blockings. Performed with FORTRAN alongside with GrADS
- Academic Consultancy Training (ACT) project against climate change and mitigation/adaptation strategies to it, conducted for a real client

2004 - 2011

B.Sc. Physics

Department of Physics of Atmosphere and Environment Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece

- Educated in a wide spectrum of natural sciences
- Participated in numerous laboratory projects
- Became able to work and manipulate large data sets

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- <u>January 2013 January 2014</u>: Member of the Educational Committee (OpCie) of the M.Sc. Programme Climate Studies (targeted to improve the ranking of the M.Sc. and to attract more students to it through meetings and discussions with the head of the department, professors, study advisor, secretary and a representation of students)
- <u>July 2007</u>: Volunteer at 1st Southeastern European Countries Games in Thessaloniki, Greece
- <u>July 2015 March 2016</u>: Fulfilling the mandatory military services in Greece